Jack Greenberg

~ Electrical and Firmware Engineer

I am a student passionate about embedded systems and interested in the intersection between hardware and software. I am also a cook, a jazz musician, and I love to play pool. I am experienced in the entire stack, from web design to bare metal.

Experience

Apple — Special Projects Group Embedded Controls Software Intern

01/2021 - 08/2021 | Sunnyvale, CA

- Wrote firmware drivers for interfacing with sensors and other hardware peripherals in embedded systems
- Worked cross-functionally with electrical, mechanical, and controls engineers to build safe and robust integrated engineering systems
- Debugged issues in multicore microcontrollers running real-time operating systems

Olin Electric Motorsports

Senior Electrical Engineer

09/2019 - Present | Olin College

- Led development of a telemetry module to stream data in real-time over radio-frequency from the car to an off-board USB receiver
- Developed mission-critical board to perform safety checking for the car, and a board for shutdown circuit monitoring

Indico Data Solutions

Backend Software Intern

05/2020 - 08/2020 | Los Angeles (remote)

- Built a Redis-based cache for user-object permissions to reduce network traffic among microservices, preventing performance bottlenecks
- Converted the entire microservices infrastructure across 17 repositories from Tornado to Asyncio coroutines with no deployment issues

Yay Brigade

Full-Stack Developer

01/2019 - 12/2019 | Los Angeles (Gap Year)

- Designed and built full-stack websites with a focus on accessibility and brand identity
- Worked closely with designers and clients to develop new brands and identities

Education

Olin College of Engineering

BS in Electrical and Computer Engineering

December 2023 | Needham, MA

- o Recipient of 4-year, 50% tuition merit scholarship.
- Notable courses include Modeling and Simulation of the Physical World, Software Systems, Computer Architecture, and Discrete Math

UCLA Extension: Networking and TCP/IP

March 2018 | Los Angeles, CA

 Studied concepts of networking technology and worked through understanding the TCP/IP stack.

Skills

Software	Database
∘ Rust	 PostgresQL
∘ C	SQLite
Python	Other o Git
 Docker 	
○ MATLAB	
	∘ KiCad

Contact

- o https://www.jackgreenberg.co
- o j@jackgreenberg.co
- o Los Angeles, CA | Boston, MA
- o Github @jack-greenberg
- 0 323-397-8961